Guide to the John Watts Papers, 1945-1982 MSS.093
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IX: Audio Recordings
  - Subseries H: Audio Recordings - Access Copies
    - Heirlooms - Section 3, [undated]; ID: 093.0125 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 093.0125)
      TRT: 00:21:05
    - Signals, [undated]; ID: 093.0128 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 092.0128)
      TRT: 00:08:53
- Series X: Video Recordings
  - Subseries A: Video Recordings - Access Copies
    - Laura Foreman Dance Company, St Peter's Church, [undated]; ID: 093.0134 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 093.0134, Box Shared Fales PM 13, Case 093.0133)
      Format: DVD
      TRT: 00:25:10
      Original Format: Super8mm
    - Laura Foreman Dance Company, St Peter's Church, [undated]; ID: 093.0135 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 093.0135)
    - [1] Glass and Shadows; [2] Glass and Shadows Random Sections, 1971; ID: 093.0144 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 093.0144, Box Shared Fales PM 13)
      TRT: 00:19:15
      Original Format: 16mm
    - [1] Glass and Shadows; [2] Glass and Shadows Random Sections, 1971; ID: 093.0145 (Box Shared Fales 125, Cd 093.0145)
  - Subseries B: Video Recordings - Originals
    Scope and Content note
    Researcher access is limited to Subseries A. Some original film may not yet be available. Please check with Fales archivist.
    - Time Coded Woman I, 3/13/1982; ID: 093.0001 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0001)
      Format: 3/4 in. Umatic
    - Time Coded Woman Intermix (Peter Ringer), 7/18/1980; ID: 093.0002 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0002)
    - Time Coded Woman I Intermix (Jody O'Brien), 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0003 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0003)
    - Time Coded Woman I Adwar Dub, 6/26/1980; ID: 093.0004 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0004)
    - Time Coded Woman III Full Version, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0005 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0005)
    - Time Coded Woman Installation Dub, 6/8/1979; ID: 093.0006 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0006)
    - Time Coded Woman III, 2/13/1982; ID: 093.0007 (Box 74A, Media ID: 093.0007)
    - Time Coded Woman III 1st Generation Dub, 3/20/1982; ID: 093.0008 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0008)
    - Time Coded Woman II, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0009 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0009)
    - Time Coded Woman II Dub E, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0010 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0010)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub 3, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0011 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0011)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub 4, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0012 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0012)
    - Time Coded Woman I Adwar Dub, 6/26/1980; ID: 093.0013 (Box 74B, Media ID: 093.0013)
    - Time Coded Woman I Intermix, 7/18/1980; ID: 093.0014 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0014)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub TO, 1/7/1980; ID: 093.0015 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0015)
    - Time Coded Woman Dub, 1978; ID: 093.0016 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0016)
    - Time Coded Woman Dub, [1979]; ID: 093.0017 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0017)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub, 3/20/1982; ID: 093.0018 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0018)
    - Time Coded Woman / Cooper Union Documentation Tape, 4/2/1982; ID: 093.0019 (Box 75A, Media ID: 093.0019)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub Work Tape, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0020 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0020)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub S, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0021 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0021)
    - Time Coded Woman I Master, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0022 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0022)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub A, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0023 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0023)
    - Time Coded Woman II Dub S, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0024 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0024)
    - Time Coded Woman II Master, 10/4/1980; ID: 093.0025 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0025)
    - Time Coded Woman II Work Tape, 10/4/1980; ID: 093.0026 (Box 75B, Media ID: 093.0026)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub 5, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0027 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0027)
    - Time Coded Woman III Master No Music, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0028 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0028)
    - Time Coded Woman III Master Version 1, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0029 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0029)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub 3, 3/20/1982; ID: 093.0030 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0030)
    - Time Coded Woman III Master Version 2, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0031 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0031)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub / T. Moore, 10/10/1979; ID: 093.0032 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0032)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub / AFI, 10/10/1979; ID: 093.0033 (Box 76A, Media ID: 093.0033)
    - Time Coded Woman III Work Tape, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0034 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0034)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub 3, 3/26/1982; ID: 093.0035 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0035)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub 2, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0036 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0036)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub 1, 11/30/1980; ID: 093.0037 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0037)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub D, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0038 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0038)
    - Time Coded Woman I BACA, 3/20/1982; ID: 093.0039 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0039)
    - Time Coded Woman I, 3/13/1982; ID: 093.0040 (Box 76B, Media ID: 093.0040)
    - Time Coded Woman II Dub G, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0041 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0041)
    - Time Coded Woman I Dub / S. Barry, 10/10/1979; ID: 093.0042 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0042)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub 7, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0043 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0043)
    - Time Coded Woman II BACA, 3/20/1982; ID: 093.0044 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0044)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub 1, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0045 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0045)
    - Time Coded Woman I Original, 6/8/1979; ID: 093.0046 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0046)
    - Time Coded Woman III Dub 3, 12/6/1980; ID: 093.0047 (Box 77A, Media ID: 093.0047)
    - UPS - Copy, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0048 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0048)
    - UPS Parsons Run Throughs, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0049 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0049)
    - Watts Electric; Laugharne, 1/14/1977; ID: 093.0050 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0050)
    - Watts Electric; MAS / Gallery Piece, 1/14/1977; ID: 093.0051 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0051)
    - Watts Electric; Elegy to Chimney, 1/14/1977; ID: 093.0052 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0052)
    - Watts Electric; Piano Forte, Maxiconcerto, 1/14/1977; ID: 093.0053 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0053)
    - Pond II (VT.), ID: 093.0054 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0054)
    - All About Electronic Music Pt. 1, [1980]; ID: 093.0055 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0055)
    - All About Electronic Music Pt. 2, [1980]; ID: 093.0056 (Box 77B, Media ID: 093.0056)
    - Laura Foreman CAPS / Multimedia, 1978; ID: 093.0057 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0057)
    - MAS - Copy, [1977]; ID: 093.0058 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0058)
    - UPS - Copy, [1977]; ID: 093.0059 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0059)
    - UPS / MAS Rehersal and Performance, 10/28/1979 - 10/29/1979; ID: 093.0060 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0060)
    - Monumental Matty; Laura Foreman Painting White, 6/24/1981; ID: 093.0061 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0061)
    - NEA: Untitled & Heirlooms, 1977; ID: 093.0062 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0062)
    - Roomwork - L. Foreman, 5/23/1981; ID: 093.0063 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0063)
    - Choreotunes Tape #1, 12/19/1980; ID: 093.0064 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0064)
    - Choreotunes Tape #2, 12/19/1980; ID: 093.0065 (Box 78A, Media ID: 093.0065)
    - [Walking Through Mirror - Laura Foreman], [1978]; ID: 093.0066 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0066)
    - [#3], [n.d.]; ID: 093.0067 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0067)
    - Truck Tape DCTV, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0068 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0068)
    - Program - Copy, 5/11/1976; ID: 093.0069 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0069)
    - Newscan, [n.d.]; ID: 093.0070 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0070)
    - Poster Tapes - Soho #1, 3/27/1981; ID: 093.0071 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0071)
    - Poster Tapes - Soho #2, 3/27/1981; ID: 093.0072 (Box 78B, Media ID: 093.0072)
    - Sheridan Square Tape #2, 5/28; ID: 093.0073 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0073)
    - Sheridan Square Tape #4, 5/28; ID: 093.0074 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0074)
    - Roomwork #1, 6/18/1981; ID: 093.0075 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0075)
    - Roomwork #2, 6/18/1981; ID: 093.0076 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0076)
    - Roomwork #3, 6/18/1981; ID: 093.0077 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0077)
    - Roomwork #4, 6/18/1981; ID: 093.0078 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0078)
    - Roomwork #5, 6/18/1981; ID: 093.0079 (Box 79A, Media ID: 093.0079)
    - Glass and Shadows # 1, [1979]; ID: 093.0080 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0080)
    - Glass and Shadows # 2, [1979]; ID: 093.0081 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0081)
    - Glass and Shadows #4 AA, 11/8/1979; ID: 093.0082 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0082)
    - Glass and Shadows #5 AB, 11/15/1979; ID: 093.0083 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0083)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub, 10/10/1979; ID: 093.0084 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0084)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub D, 10/26/1979; ID: 093.0085 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0085)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub C, 10/26/1979; ID: 093.0086 (Box 79B, Media ID: 093.0086)
    - Glass and Shadows - NEA, 10/10/1979; ID: 093.0087 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0087)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub TD, 1/9/1980; ID: 093.0088 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0088)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub TM Master, 1/9/1980; ID: 093.0089 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0089)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub TE, 1/9/1980; ID: 093.0090 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0090)
    - Untitled, 1/19/1979; ID: 093.0091 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0091)
    - Untitled with Metronome, 3/30/1979; ID: 093.0092 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0092)
    - Untitled Dub, 12/21/1978; ID: 093.0093 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0093)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub HTA, 1/9/1980; ID: 093.0094 (Box 79C, Media ID: 093.0094)
    - Untitled - Guggenheim Tape #1, 1978; ID: 093.0095 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0095)
    - Untitled - Guggenheim Tape #2, 1978; ID: 093.0096 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0096)
    - Untitled - Remastered Dub, 1/19/1979; ID: 093.0097 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0097)
    - Untitled - Technisphere Dub, 5/10/1979; ID: 093.0098 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0098)
    - Untitled - Technisphee Dub, No Titles, 5/10/1979; ID: 093.0099 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0099)
    - Untitled - Dub Remastered, 1/19/1979 [1978]; ID: 093.0100 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0100)
    - Untitled - Rough Edit, 5/10/1979; ID: 093.0101 (Box 80A, Media ID: 093.0101)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub TA, 1/9/1980; ID: 093.0102 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0102)
    - Glass and Shadows Dub 4, 11/15/1980; ID: 093.0103 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0103)
    - Untitled - Dub A, 10/26/1979; ID: 093.0104 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0104)
    - Untitled - Remastered Dub, 1/19/1979 [1978]; ID: 093.0105 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0105)
    - Laura Foreman - Heirlooms; a duex, 1977; ID: 093.0106 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0106)
    - Laura Foreman - Untitled, Heirlooms; a duex, 1977; ID: 093.0107 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0107)
    - Live From Cannes; A Rock and Roll Special, 12/5/1979; ID: 093.0108 (Box 80B, Media ID: 093.0108)
- Series XI: Film
  - Subseries A: Film - Access Copies
    - Laura Foreman Dance Company, St Peter's Church (answer print), [undated]; ID: 093.0130 (Reel 093.0130)
      Format: 16mm
    - Laura Foreman Dance Company, St Peter's Church (release print), [undated]; ID: 093.0131 (Box Shared Fales 048, Reel 093.0131)
    - Glass and Shadows (answer print), 1971; ID: 093.0137 (Reel 093.0137)
      TRT: 00:18:30
    - Glass and Shadows (release print), 1971; ID: 093.0138 (Box Shared Fales 048, Reel 093.0138)
    - Glass and Shadows; Random Sections (answer print), 1971; ID: 093.0140 (Reel 093.0140)
      TRT: 00:00:45
    - Glass and Shadows; Random Sections (release print), 1971; ID: 093.0141 (Box Shared Fales 049, Reel 093.0141)
    - Glass and Shadows; Random Sections (D/N) (Reel 093.0139)
  - Subseries B: Film - Originals
    - Laura Foreman Dance Company; St. Peter's Church, [1970]; ID: 093.0110 (Case 093.0110)
      Format: Super 8 mm
    - Glass & Shadows June 1971 - Complete Choreographic Record, 6/1971; ID: 093.0111 (Case 093.0111)
    - Glass & Shadows - selections at random, 6/1971 [processed 1972]; ID: 093.0112A (Case 093.0112A)
    - [War], [n.d.]; ID: 093.0146 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0146)
      Format: 16 mm
    - Your Daisies Are Numbered (Reel 1), [n.d.]; ID: 093.0147 (Reel 093.0147)
    - Your Daisies Are Numbered (Reel 2), [n.d.]; ID: 093.0148 (Reel 093.0148)
    - Your Daisies Are Numbered (Reel 3), [n.d.]; ID: 093.0149 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0149)
    - [Glass and Shadows Documentary], ID: 093.0150 (Case 093.0150)
    - [Fable Fair], 1963; ID: 093.0151 (Case 093.0151)
      Format: 8 mm
    - [Theatrical Preview for the New York Erotic Film Festival], 1972; ID: 093.0152 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0152)
    - [Preview/Trailer for 2nd Annual New York Erotic Film Festival], 1972; ID: 093.0153 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0153)
    - [Preview/Traiiler for 2nd Annual New York Erotic Film Festical], 1972; ID: 093.0154 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0154)
    - [Glass And Shadows - Universal Leader #'s AH-May 7-9, 1971], ID: 093.0155 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0155)
    - [Biu's Film Print], [n.d.]; ID: 093.0156 (Case 093.0156)
    - [Demo: 'Laserset' Gilbert Trythall], 1966; ID: 093.0157 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0157)
    - [Memorials and Freedom Dancer's Film], 1963; ID: 093.0158 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0158)
    - [Epicycles - Copy], 1969; ID: 093.0159 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0159)
    - [UNID - Dance Film], [n.d.]; ID: 093.0160 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0160)
    - [Dancer], 1967; ID: 093.0161 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0161)
    - [Epicycles - Original], 1969; ID: 093.0162 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0162)
    - Epicycles, 1970; ID: 093.0163 (Box Media, Media ID: 093.0163)
  - Subseries C: Film - Unprocessed Materials (Box 81)
- Series XII: Props and Personal Items
  - Hockey mask; Halloween mask, undated (Box 84, Folder data_value_missing_046baa65486db7f60f69c5aa21604698)
  - Captain's hat; harmonicas; keys, undated (Box 84, Folder data_value_missing_e42accb2e997ed0f4f602b025a213317)
  - Modern Dance Power button; matches, undated (Box 84, Folder data_value_missing_79d68b1a1d365297b9989a88ee0e3359)
  - Carved wooden nested jars., undated (Box 84, Folder data_value_missing_b4a55ba8f94bcb4bb2646ccbfd591929)
  - Wall plaque: To John Watts from Percy Sutton, President of the Borough of Manhattan 1974 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Wall plaque: Fellow John Watts, International Conference of Weekly Newspaper Editors, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Wall plaque: U.S. Bald Eagle Command, Commemoration of the First American Bald Eagle Day, June 20, 1976. (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Props - signs, undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Props - video title cards, undated (Box 86, Folder 2)
- Oversize - Series I: Music Scores
  - Fable Fair (Aesop's Fable Fair) (1972) [Theatre piece for Children, script by Joyce Doolittle; piano (4-Hands), clarinet, trumpet, violin, percussion (2); score and parts] (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Keepsakes (1978) [orchestra and tape; full score] (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Keepsakes [parts and score copies], undated (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Le Match de Boxe (Salute a Marcel Duchamp) (1977) [Piano with percussion; full score] (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Processional (1978) [score] (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Processional [parts], undated (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Time Coded woman (1982) [full score, video script, parts] (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Unidentified [Piano 4-Hands?], undated (Box 10, Folder 69)
- Oversize - Series VI: Publicity Materials
  - Poster Art for Newsletter, CCT Review, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Poster Advertisement - Aesop's Fable Fair, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Ads, Posters - various, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
- Oversize - Series VII: Printed Material
  - Printed material (oversize) Celli, Joseph "The Organic Oboe" info & press kit, undated (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Printed material (oversize) Woodman, William, cartoons & drawings, undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Manhattan East News; issues edited by John Watts (1965-68), 1965-1968 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Life Magazine (2 issues: MLK, and Humphrey Pres. nomination; 1968, 69), 1968-1969 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - New York Times 1977 electricity blackout issue (photo of the "new" Twin Towers) (Box 87, Folder 3)
- Oversize - Series XII: Personal Items
  - Charles Bunnel (1897-1968); artist's painting 1961 (Watt's painting instructor at the University of Colorado in late 1950s) (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Charles Bunnel (1897-1968); artist's painting 1961 (Box 88, Folder 5)